等等  求你
Wait! Please!
我们可以谈谈的
We can talk about this!
不要  不要
No! No!
不要啊
No!!
犯罪是
A crime is a wrong
危害公务的过错
arising from the violation of a public duty.
侵权是
A tort is a wrong
危害私人责任的过错
arising from the violation of a private duty.
没错
Yes.
好了  我觉得我的脑子要挤爆了
Okay. I think my brain is crammed to the limit.
我觉得你和你的脑子已经准备好了
Well, I think you and your brain are more than ready.
阿丽克西斯  你今早不是有期中考吗
Hey, Alexis. Don't you have a midterm this morning?
我这就走
I'm leaving now.
贝克特在帮我临时回顾呢
Beckett was just giving me a last-minute review.
-再见  -再见
- Bye. - Bye.
多谢帮忙
Thanks for your help.
再见
Bye.
好运哦
Good luck!
她脑子很好使的
You know, she's got an amazing brain.
如果她想  可以做个好律师的
I mean, if she wanted to, she'd make an incredible lawyer.
是啊  我本来就已经说不过她了
Yeah. Like I don't lose enough arguments to her already.
那你呢
What about you?
你会后悔没去上法学院吗
You ever regret it, not getting your law degree?
我宁可抓到罪犯  而不是送他们进监狱
Um, I'd rather take criminals down than send them up.
是嘛
Really?
因为就凭你的头脑
Because with your mind
你肯定能当上大法官的
bet you could have made chief justice.
你拥有一切资质
You have all the qualifications.
你聪明  令人敬畏
You're smart, you are intimidating,
-而且你穿袍子非常好看  -是嘛
- And you look very, very good in a robe. - Really?
想去我的内廷休息10分钟吗
Care to take a 10-minute recess in my chambers?
如果庭上允许  我愿意
If it please the court, I would.
看来得延期了
I think we're gonna need a continuance.
反对
Uh, objection.
反对无效
Overruled.
莱恩  说吧
Ryan, give it to me.
抱歉  卡塞尔  不会说的
Sorry, Castle. I'm not telling.
太可惜了  我已经知道了
That's too bad. I already know.
约翰·传奇  《我紧握你的一切》
It's John Legend, "All of me cuffed all of you."
才不是
No.
等等  你们是在说
Wait a minute. Are... are you guys
警察慈善捐款晚会吗
talking about the policeman's benevolent fundraiser?
是啊  才艺大赛周五晚举行
Yeah, the talent competition is on Friday night,
但他不肯说他和埃斯波要唱什么
but he won't tell me what he and Espo are doing.
你们要怎么超越
So, how are you guys even gonna top
去年的《辣身舞》举舞伴那一段啊
the "Dirty Dancing" lift scene from last year?
《今生之罪》  埃斯波/莱恩的经典作品啊
"Crime of Our Lives." Classic Espo/Ryan.
放心吧  作为两届冠军
No, rest assured, as two-time champs,
不管我们做什么  都会震惊四座的
whatever we do is gonna blow the rest of the field away.
那是因为我不是警察  不能参加
Well, that's only because, not being a cop, I'm ineligible.
但如果我能和贝克特一起参赛
But if Beckett and I were competing,
你们就别想连冠了
you'd be out a trophy.
是啊  我们绝对能击败你们
Oh, yeah. We'd so take you down.
别做白日梦了
Well, back in reality,
环卫工人今早发现了无名男尸
our John Doe was found this morning by sanitation workers.
没有电话或钱包
No phone, no wallet.
死因
Cause?
后脑遭重击
Blunt-force trauma to the back of the head.
可能是一截管子或者棒球棒
Probably a pipe or a baseball bat.
从尸斑看  死亡时间
Based on lividity, I'd say it happened
是午夜12点到凌晨2点间
between 12:00 and 2:00 a.m. this morning.
有目击者吗
Any witnesses?
附近的一名居民凌晨1点左右听到了尖叫
A guy who lives nearby heard screams around 1:00 a.m.
往窗外看  看到一辆车加速离开
He looked out his window. He saw a car speeding away.
看到车型了吗
He get a make and model?
只能看到尾灯  但他说看着像跑车
Just taillights. But he said it looked like a sports car.
我和莱恩会继续找目击证人
Ryan and I are gonna keep looking for witnesses
和街头监控录像
and street-cam footage,
但这里是工业区  监控覆盖不全
but it's an industrial area, so coverage is spotty.
等等  我好像认识他
Wait a minute. I think I know this guy.
他是人身伤害律师
He's that personal-injury attorney on tv
深夜电视上有他的广告
who has the late-night ads.
天呐  没错  就是他...
Oh, my god! You're right! That's, uh...
-斗牛犬  -斗牛犬
- The pitbull. - The pitbull.
斗牛犬
The pitbull?
是啊  斗牛犬里奇·法科
Yeah. Richie "The pitbull" Falco.
拜托  你肯定见过那个广告
Come on, man. You've seen the ads.
人头狗身
A guy's head on a dog's body.
"出事故了吗  抓住法律的尾巴吧"
"You been in an accident? Take the law by the tail."
"拿到一个你应得的和解"
"And get a bite at the settlement you deserve."
"我会让法律..."
"I'll make the law"...
唯你是从
Your bitch!
"斗牛犬还会说西班牙语"
"El Pitbull tambien halbla Espanol."
为什么只有我没看过这个广告啊
Why am I the only one who's never seen this commercial?
因为是深夜广告
Because it comes on late at night,
你即使不做兼职
and when you're not moonlighting,
你个喝蜜蜂奶的也10点就睡了
your honey-milk-sipping ass is in bed by 10:00.
怎么会有人想杀斗牛犬啊
Why would anyone want to kill the pitbull?
或许鉴证组能找到凶器
Maybe CSU will get lucky and find the murder weapon.
我们先把尸体运回停尸房
Meanwhile, let's get the body to the morgue
看看有什么发现
and see what it can tell us.
卡塞尔  我们去一趟斗牛犬的办公室
Castle, you and I should go to pitbull's office,
看看能发现什么
see what we can find there.
出事故了吗
Been in an accident?
抓住法律的尾巴
Take the law by the tail
拿到一个你应得的和解
and get a bite at the settlement you deserve.
我会为小人物而战
I'll fight for you, the little guy,
因为斗牛犬和落水狗要统一阵线
because pitbulls and underdogs stick together.
记住  我会让法律唯你是从
Remember, I'll make the law your bitch!
汪汪
Ruff!
Ruff! Ruff!
里奇的委托人虽然不好受
Richie's clients may be suffering,
但他的生意可很火爆
but his business sure wasn't.
想寻求尽快和解的人
Yeah, well, there's always gonna be people
从来不缺
looking for a quick settlement
而里奇这样的底层投机者
and plenty of opportunistic bottom-feeders like Richie
就会帮他们拿到钱
ready to help them cash in.
一半人肯定都是装的
I bet half these people are faking.
看到那个人了吗
See that guy over there?
看好了  打扰  先生
Watch this. Excuse me, sir?
能帮我扔掉吗
Could you throw this away for me?
抱歉  我准头...有点
Sorry. My aim is...A little...
或许...他可能是真的
Maybe... he's probably legit.
抱歉让你们久等  各位
Sorry for the wait, folks.
斗牛犬肯定随时就会到的
I'm sure pitbull will be here any minute.
他最近几天的样子
The way h-he's been acting the last few days, I...
我就知道出事了
...I knew something was wrong.
他怎么了
How was he acting?
焦躁  多疑
Anxious. Paranoid.
他离开办公室前  他会往窗外看
Before he'd leave the office, he'd look out the window.
就好像他觉得有人可能在监视他
It's like he thought someone might be watching him.
昨天早上
And yesterday morning,
他还打电话说他不来了
He called to say that he wasn't coming in at all.
这不寻常吗
Was that unusual?
他从不请假
He never missed a day
我都给他干三年了
in the three years I worked for him.
你知道是出什么事了吗
Do you know what was going on?
他不肯说
He wouldn't talk about it.
我问他是不是跟我们的案子有关
I-I-I asked if it had something to do with one of the cases,
他
and he...
他说不是  还叫我别担心
...he said no, and he, uh, told me not to worry...
说一切很快就会过去
...and that it would all be over soon.
他跟谁有矛盾吗
Was he having any problems with anyone?
客户  或者女友
Uh, clients? A girlfriend?
他没有女友
He...didn't have a girlfriend.
我一直想...
I kept hoping, but...
我知道你们在想什么
Look, I... I know what you guys are thinking.
人身伤害律师是人渣  对吧
Personal-injury lawyers are gutter rats, right?
但里奇不一样
But Richie was different.
他是真心的
He really cared.
他认为制定法律是为了保护所有人
He thought the law was there to protect everyone
而不只是保护那些请的起律师的公司
And not just corporations who could afford it.
他的客户也因此爱戴他
And his clients, they loved him for it.
他的对手呢
And his adversaries?
当然  被他起诉的人有时候会很愤怒
S-sure, people he sued got pissed sometimes.
他获得过大笔的和解费
I mean, he won some big settlements.
但我想不到有什么能为他招来杀机
But nothing I can imagine anyone killing for.
克莱恩女士  整理出他手头所有的在办案件
Ms. Klein, I need a list of all of his active cases,
还有在过去几年里他打赢的所有官司
along with anyone that he's won a judgment against
我要这些案件的清单
over the last few years.
好的
Of course.
据我了解  法科先生住在布鲁克林
So, I understand that Mr. Falco lived in brooklyn.
是  就在公园坡
Yeah -- Park Slope.
他的尸体却在汉密尔顿高地
His body was found in Hamilton heights.
你知道他昨晚在那儿做什么吗
Do you have any idea what he was doing up there last night?
圣西蒙医院在那儿
St. Simon's is up there.
圣西蒙医院吗
The hospital?
嗯  有时候他会去急诊室转转
Yes. Sometimes he would do the rounds at emergency rooms
看有没有人需要他帮忙
to see if anyone needed his services.
收到你短信了  有什么要告诉我们的吗
Got your text. You have something for us?
当然  我知道被害人死前在做什么
Yep. I know what your victim was doing before he died.
做什么
What?
你们先说
You first.
我知道了  她想知道我们的节目
I get it. She wants us to tell her about our routine.
你知道我们不能泄露秘密的
Uh, you know that we cannot be giving that away, girl.
要知道的话就像别人一样买票吧
You are gonna have to buy a ticket, just like everyone else.
你发现了什么
Now, what have you got?
好吧
Fine.
斗牛犬在乡下待过一段时间
Pitbull spent some time in the countryside.
这些黏糊糊的黄色粉末
You see this sticky yellow powder
粘在里奇长裤的踝关节位置  看到没
on Richie's pant leg about ankle high?
这是款冬花的花粉
Pollen from the tussilago flower, also know as coltsfoot.
城市里没有款冬花  所以不是在这儿粘的
It's not found in the city, so it didn't happen here.
还有别的线索
But there's something else --
这可比花间嬉戏没趣多了
Something a lot less fun than frolicking in the flowers.
这些是电击枪的痕迹
Those are taser marks.
他遭受过折磨
He was tortured?
是  蕾妮说他身上这些伤
Yeah, Lanie says the injuries he sustained
是在他死前一小时内留下的
were within an hour of his death.
那么  要么凶手想从他那里得到什么
So either the killer wanted something from him,
而斗牛犬不肯松口
something Pitbull didn't want to give up...
要么凶手想让他受折磨
Or the killer wanted him to suffer.
这可能和他以前的案件有关联
This might have something to do with one of his old cases.
但他的客户列表里没什么不寻常
Yeah, but nothing jumped out from his client list.
都是些失足意外  工人赔偿  保险索赔之类的
It's all slip-and-falls, workmen's comp, insurance claims --
没什么能解释他为什么受折磨
Nothing that would explain torture
或是为什么要出城
or a trip outside of the city.
他去哪儿了
So where did he go?
卡塞尔先生  聊聊
Mr. Castle? A word?
当然
Of course.
你也知道  这周五要举办警方慈善协会才艺大赛
As you know, the PBA talent competition is this friday,
每年我们都会邀请名人表演
And every year, we line up a celebrity to perform.
对  为了多卖门票嘛
Yeah, to help boost ticket sales.
今年坎莫尔[脱口秀主持人]不来吗
Isn't Kimmel doing it this year?
本来说好了的
He was supposed to,
-但由于临时冲突  他不来了  -不会吧
- but due to a last-second conflict, he just dropped out, - What?!
他们告诉我要找个名人替补
and I've been told we need a replacement celebrity.
他们让我来邀请你
I've been asked to ask you.
要让我表演
You want me to perform?
我俩都会从中得到亟需的总局的友善对待
It would earn us both some much-needed goodwill down at 1pp.
票卖不出去怎么办嘞
But what about ticket sales?
我和贝克特很高兴去表演
Beckett and I would be happy to.
等等  什么
Wait. What?
有一个条件
On one condition.
尽管我不是个警察  我也得有资格争奖杯哦
Even though I'm not a cop, we compete for the trophy.
没问题
Done.
卡塞尔
Oh, Castle.
你还真以为你有机会争奖杯啊
You really don't think you have a shot at winning that trophy?
有很大机会呢
Oh, I think I have more than just a shot.
卡塞尔
Castle?
你知道我和莱恩排练好久了吧
You do understand that me and Ryan have been rehearsing for months?
我和贝克特之间都不用排练
Well, what Beckett and I have cannot be rehearsed.
我们之间是化学反应  心灵相通
It's chemistry -- that intuitive bond,
彼此知道对方的想法
each person knowing what the other's thinking.
卡塞尔  我们能到那儿聊一下吗
Castle. Can we talk for a second over there?
我早知道她要这么说
I knew she was gonna say that.
你不觉得拖我参加之前
Don't you think you should have...asked me
需要先问一下我的意见吗
before signing me up for this?
我以为你是同意的
I thought you were on board.
之前你还跟莱恩夸下海口呢
Uh, you were trash-talking Ryan about it before.
但当时我没想到我们真有机会
Yeah, that's when I thought that there was no chance in hell
参加这个比赛
that we would actually do it.
放轻松  我们就演平时的节目就好
Oh, relax. We'll just do our routine.
我们没有节目啊
We don't have a routine.
拜托  浴室里唱的那回呢  多愉快啊
Come on! That thing in the shower? That is delightful.
不  那不算数
No. That's not a routine.
那就是俩裸身男女
That's two naked people singing
在没人看到或听到的时候放声歌唱而已
when there's no one around to see or hear it.
那么我们就加上舞步加上服装
So we'll add some dance steps and clothes.
稳赢不输啊
It's can't-miss.
伙计们
Uh, guys?
哥们儿  等会儿
Give them a second, bro.
他俩在排练心灵感应呢
They're rehearsing their chemistry.
莱恩  你有什么线索了吗
Ryan, you got something?
对  里奇昨晚确实在圣西蒙医院
Yeah -- turns out that richie was at st. Simon's last night,
而且他不是独自一人
and he was not alone.
这是圣西蒙医院后面的一个停车场
All right, so, here is the parking lot behind st. Simon's.
里奇在那儿
There's Richie.
看着
Now watch this.
是辆跑车
It's a sports car --
逃离罪案现场的也是
Like the one seen fleeing the crime scene.
显然车主和斗牛犬有些过节
And apparently, the driver had some kind of bf with pitbull.
车主把他塞进车里  然后开车离开了
He shoves him in the car and drives off.
能看清车牌吗
Can we make out the plate?
可以  已经查过了
Yeah. Already ran it.
是在这人名下的
It is registered to this guy --
德里克·博尔特
Derek Bolt.
闪电德里克·博尔特  橄榄球联盟的前任跑锋
Derek "Lightning" Bolt, the ex-nfl running back?
前最有价值球员和斗牛犬有什么关联呢
What's a former mvp doing with our ambulance-chasing pitbull?
不会是好事  看看时间
Nothing good. Check out the time stamp.
晚上11点  就在里奇被杀前几个小时
11:00 p.M. -- just hours before richie was killed.
有足够的时间先折磨他
Leaving enough time for him to be tortured first.
就是他
There he is.
德里克·博尔特
Derek bolt?
我们想和你谈谈
We'd like a word.
该死  放开我
Aw, man! Get off me, man!
博尔特  你被逮捕了
Guess what, bolt. You just got benched.
终于来人了
Finally!
有人给我解释一下为什么抓我吗
Someone gonna explain to me what I'm doing in here?
那你看到我们就跑
So, I guess you running away from us
是在怎么着  锻炼吗  里克
was, what, exercise, Derek?
拜托  我又不知道你们是警察
Hey, I didn't know you were cops.
听着  我遇到点财政问题好吧
Look, I got some financial troubles, all right?
你俩看起来像收债的
And you two looked like collection agents,
所以我的直觉就是跑了再说啊
so my instincts kicked in.
闪电可以离开全美橄榄球联盟
You can take lightning out of the NFL,
但你夺不走闪电的橄榄球本能啊
But you can't the NFL out of lightning, you know.
我们很清楚你的财政问题  里克
We know all about your financial troubles, Derek.
没错  我们知道
Yeah, we were just reading
你去年被人狠狠告了
how you got hit with a lawsuit last year
因为你在一家夜店外打了人
after you busted up some guy outside of a club.
当然要打  他撞凹了我的闪电车
Hell yeah. He dented the bolt-mobile.
我当时头脑发热
Look, I lost my head, all right?
但我后来再没找过他麻烦
But I've left him alone since.
闪电可不会出击两次
Lightning don't strike twice.
不过你可没怎么原谅他的律师  对吧
Except you weren't so forgiving of his lawyer, were you?
斗牛犬
Pitbull?
他跟这事有什么关系
What's he got to do with any of this?
他去年达成了一项对你很不利的庭外和解
He won a big settlement against you last year
让你破了产
and sent you into bankruptcy.
所以呢
So?
所以斗牛犬死了  里克
So pitbull's dead, Derek.
-什么  -而他最后一次被人看到
- What? - And the last time he was seen,
就是昨晚11点被你推进了闪电车
he was being shoved into your bolt-mobile at 11:00 p.m.
不是看起来那样
Hey, hey, that -- that ain't what it looks like.
是吗  目前看来这就是复仇
Really? Because right now, it looks like revenge.
我没杀斗牛犬  好吧
I-I did not kill Pitbull, all right?
他在法庭上针对我时表现太好了
Look, dawg did such a good job against me in court,
我想让他加入我的团队
I wanted him on my team.
所以我去雇了他
So I went and hired his ass.
你雇了里奇
Richie was working for you?
那你怎么不在他的客户名单里
Well, then why weren't you on his client list?
我找他是因为亲子鉴定这种事
It's a paternity thing, all right?
我老婆快受不了我了
My old lady's just about had it with me,
所以他是在私下处理的
so he was handling this off the books.
但这也不能解释
Okay, but none of that
你昨晚强迫他上车的事
explains your little joyride last night.
我和里奇昨天下午
Me and Richie were supposed to meet up
本来要跟我孩他妈和她的律师团队碰面的
with my baby mama and her lawyer yesterday afternoon.
可里奇没出现  让我非常丢脸
Only, Richie never showed up, and it made me look bad.
所以我请他上我的车小聊了一下
So I invited him into my car for a little conversation.
他说他很抱歉
He said he was sorry
说临时遇到点紧急业务
and that some urgent business matter came up.
什么业务
What kind of business?
关于结算债务的
Something about settling a debt.
他说他会处理我的事
He told me he'd handle my thing,
但希望我能稍他去个什么餐厅
but he wanted me to take him to some diner
他晚上要在那见个人
for a late-night meet.
说事关人命
Said someone's life depended on it.
看来就是他的命啊
Guess maybe it was his.
24小时健身房的经理证实了
So, the manager at the 24-hour gym
里奇被杀期间
confirms that Derek was working out there
里克正在那里健身
during Richie's time-of-death window,
他不是凶手
So he's not our killer.
也就是说里克说把里奇捎到了餐厅
Which means derek might have been telling the truth
可能是实话
about dropping richie off at that diner.
我过去查查
Yeah, I'll head over there,
看有没有服务员记得
see if the waitstaff remembers richie
里奇昨晚跟什么人说过话
talking with anyone last night.
这还是不能解释他白天在哪里
It still doesn't explain where he was during the day,
他为什么翘班  爽约没去参加客户面谈
why he missed work or blew off that client meeting.
也许我知道可以问谁
I may know someone we can ask.
埃斯波  你怎么了
Espo, what happened?
我放倒闪电的时候扭到了膝盖
I twisted my knee when I was tackling lightning.
你这...没事吧
Wh... are you gonna be okay?
没事  就是扭了一下
Yeah, I'll be fine. I just, uh...I just tweaked it.
可能扭伤了
It's probably a sprain.
那可太糟了
Oh, that's too bad.
我还想在才艺大赛上打败你呢
I was looking forward to beating you in the talent competition.
你以为这会让我退出吗
You think this is gonna take me out?
对  我觉得会
Yes. Yes, I do.
不  我还是要上
No. It's still on.
这...怎么上
Uh, ge-- I-I-I mean, how?
埃斯波  你连路都走不了了
Espo, you can barely walk.
是  但就算只有一条腿
Yeah, and even on one leg,
我跟莱恩还是会完爆你们
Ryan and I are still gonna whip your sorry asses.
这样吧  打个赌怎么样
In fact, how about a wager?
搭档  也许我们该商量下...
Um, uh, partner, you know, maybe w-we should discuss --
要是我们赢了  你下本书就要写
If we win, then you will dedicate your next book
献给埃斯波西托和莱恩
To "Esposito and Ryan,
两个比我幽默  比我帅气
"Two guys who are funnier, handsomer,
在各方面都胜过我的人
and better than me in every way."
你说真的啊
Oh, you're serious.
那要是我和贝克特赢了呢
And if Beckett and I win?
那我和莱恩就会叫你
Well, then Ryan and I
"卡塞尔大帝"  叫一个月
will call you "King Castle" for a month.
哈维...
Hey, Javi --
我是说...
I mean --
-怎么样  -知道吗
- What do you say? - Yeah, you know what?
我同意莱恩
I think Ryan's right.
我们没必要为这事打赌吧
I mean, we don't need to make a bet out of this.
为什么  因为你是懦夫
Why? Because you're chicken?
不  因为我是个成年人
No. Because I am a grown-up.
是啊  成年懦夫
Yeah -- a grown-up chicken.
你们叫我"殿下"也行
I will also accept "Your royal highness."
就这么定了  跛子
You're on, gimpy.
这话够狠
That's clever.
这叫现炒现卖
I work with what you give me.
我一定会拿下你
I'm gonna take you down.
用什么拿  你的拐杖吗
With what -- your crutches?
咱们能回到死者身上了吗
Can we get back to the dead guy?
你说你找到个人
You said that you found someone
能告诉我们里奇昨天为什么翘了工作
who could tell us why Richie missed work yesterday.
对  我查了他的电话和财务记录
Yes. I pulled his phone and financials.
他的信用卡昨天没有消费记录
There were no charges on his credit card yesterday,
但他打过一个电话
but he made a call --
昨天一整天  他只打了这一个电话
The only call he made from his cell all day.
打给谁了
To whom?
一个他多年没联系过的人
Someone he hasn't called in years --
他的前妻  艾丽莎·莱斯纳
His ex-wife, Elise Resner.
他说遇到了麻烦  需要我的帮助
He said he was in trouble and needed my help.
具体什么样的麻烦
What kind of trouble, exactly?
探长  你得明白
Detective, you have to understand --
我已经多年没跟他联系过了
I hadn't spoken to him in years.
然后他就突然打来了电话
And then he just calls out of the blue.
你根本没问
You never asked.
我根本不想知道
I didn't want to know.
经过了我跟他之间发生的那些事
After everything that happened between us,
我知道我不能再被卷进去了
I knew I couldn't get involved again.
你们之间发生了什么
What happened between the two of you?
我们以前在同一家企业法律所
We were at the same corporate firm.
我们就是在那相识的
It's how we met.
企业法
Corporate law?
他怎么成了个受理人身伤害的律师
How did he end up a personal-injury attorney?
他当年可是业内巨星
He was a superstar --
上过《哈佛法学评论》  有机会当合伙人
Harvard law review, partner track.
但后来一定是压力太大了
But the pressure got to be too much for him.
大约五年前  他开始堕落
About five years back, he self-destructed --
酗酒  吸毒
drinking, drugs...
输掉所有的官司  丢了工作
losing all of his cases, uh, his job...
最后也失去了我
then, finally, me.
贝克特  有情况
Hey, Beckett, we got a situation.
我吃完午餐回来  发现门半开着
I came back from lunch to find the door half-open,
锁被撬了
the lock was broken,
还有...其他的你们都看到了
and -- well, you can -- you can see the rest.
知道他们是在找什么吗
Any idea what they were looking for?
我还在清点东西
I'm still sorting through the mess.
不过里奇的电脑不见了
But Richie's computer is gone,
而且还有别的
And there's something else.
他所有案卷都不见了
All of his case files are missing.
为什么有人要偷里奇的案卷
Why would anyone want Richie's files?
肯定和他之前处理的某件案子有关...
This must have something to do with one of his cases --
某个客户  或是某个证人...
Client, maybe a witness...
被他调查过的某个人或某件事
Someone or something that he was looking into,
他连你都不愿告诉的事情
something he was hiding even from you.
我们先排查这幢楼
Okay, let's canvass the building,
看看有没有人看到了什么
see if anyone else saw something.
叫鉴证科的人过来
And get CSU down here.
指纹  纤维  DNA等等
Prints, fibers, DNA -- the whole thing.
好的
Right.
抱歉
Excuse me.
是我
It's me.
你还记得那个里奇说的
Do you remember that meeting
他昨晚在一个餐厅和别人的会面吗
that Richie said he had in a diner last night?
是的
Yeah.
一个服务生看到了整个过程
Well, a waitress saw the whole thing.
不如说是场吵架
A lot more like a fight.
里奇和另外一个人吵的不可开交
Richie got in a shouting match with another guy.
有相貌描述吗
You get a description?
比那个更好
Uh, better than that.
服务生都认出那个人是谁了
Waitress knew exactly who he was.
马上给你发照片过去
I'll send you a picture.
这是阿奇·布朗斯坦
That's Archie Bronstein,
"草原巨锤"
"The Savannah Hammer."
里奇和这人会因为什么吵起来吗
Is there any reason that Richie and the Hammer would be fighting?
他们经常互相窃取对方的客户
They were always stealing clients from each other.
只不过里奇更厉害一点
Only, Richie was better at it.
终于锤子受不了老是输给他
It got to where Hammer was so sick of losing business to him
他就...
that he...
他就说一定给这事儿做个了结
He promised to put an end to it.
不论如何
One way or another.
我们怎么才能找到他
Where can we find him?
给我打电话  朋友
Call me, friend.
发生在你身上的事
Whatever happened to you is nothing
和我要对那家伙做的根本不值一提
compared to what I'm gonna do to the other guy.
阿奇·布朗斯坦先生
Mr. Archie Bronstein?
叫我草原巨锤
The Savannah Hammer.
案子再小也要做  和解多大都要争取
No case too small, no settlement too big.
有什么能为你们效劳的吗
Now, what can I help you with?
滑到摔跤  工伤  医疗事故
Slip-and-fall? Work injury? Medical malpractice?
我们是为斗牛犬里奇的被害而来的
We're here about the murder of Richie the Pitbull.
是的  那晚我是在那个餐厅
Sure, I was at that diner last night.
你们俩的这个紧急会面...
This urgent meeting that the two of you had --
是关于什么的
What was it about?
我觉得根本不能算是会面
I'd hardly call it a meeting.
我就是想去吃个核桃派的
I went in to get some pecan pie,
然后就看到他坐在那里
and I saw him sitting there.
这个会面不是事先安排好的
So the meeting wasn't planned?
也许他本打算和别的什么人碰面的吧
Well, maybe he was planning on meeting someone else,
反正我看到他在那个隔间里的时候
but when I saw him in that booth,
他就一个人  然后我们就吵了起来
he was alone, and we got into it.
吵什么了
About what?
就是那些...我昨晚在这儿
The usual -- I caught him here last night
抓到他想偷走我的一个客户
trying to poach one of my clients.
在这儿吵了一架然后餐厅又吵了
We had words here and then again at the diner.
里奇一直妄想觉得被跟踪了
So, Richie was paranoid he was being followed,
消失整天不见  说他有麻烦了
disappears all day, says he's in trouble,
然后还到这儿来偷你的客户
then comes here to poach a client?
布朗斯坦先生  有什么具体的原因
Mr. Bronstein, was there a specific reason
让他对这个客户这么感兴趣吗
that he was interested in this client?
他觉得这个案子很好弄
He smelled an easy win.
可怜女孩的车被收旧货的卡车撞上
Poor girl gets three pieces of flying metal in her heart
三个金属碎片插进了心脏
when a scrap truck plows into her car.
是个板上钉钉的和解案
Now, that is a slam-dunk settlement.
所以看到他在餐厅的时候
So you bet when I saw Richie at that diner,
自然就吵了起来
we got loud.
服务生最后让我们出去解决问题
So the waitress told us to take it outside,
我就跟他说最好离我的客户远一点
where I advised him to steer clear of my clients.
那时候是几点
And what time was that?
大约11:45
11:45 maybe.
听着  我没有杀他
Look, I didn't kill him.
我也没有偷那些案卷
I didn't steal those files.
不过这一切说不定和
But it might be related
他的..."课外活动"有关
to his... extracurricular activities.
什么意思
Uh, what's that mean?
里奇总觉得他比我们都要厉害
Richie liked to come off like he was better than all of us,
就因为他有哈佛的学位
with his Harvard degree
和他为小人物伸冤的那套样子
and his "champion of the little guy" act,
相信我...他卷入了一些事
but trust me -- he was into some things.
什么样的事
What kind of things?
坏事
Bad things.
外面流传的说法是
Word on the street was,
只要开价  没有什么他不会做的
there was nothing he wouldn't do for a price.
无论什么事
And I mean nothing.
看来"锤子"并不是凶手
So, it looks like Hammer's not our killer.
显然  在离开餐厅之后
Apparently, after he left the diner,
他整晚都在花费心思"争取"一位客户
he spent the rest of the night "nailing" one of his clients.
除了案卷和电脑之外
Anything else turn up missing
还有什么东西不见了吗
besides the files and the computer?
没  目前还没有
No, not so far.
这我就不太明白了...
This is what I don't get --
如果他们就想要案卷的话
If all they wanted was files,
为何还要把这里翻个底朝天呢
why'd they turn this place upside down?
一定是在找其他什么东西
Must have been looking for something else.
警探们  你们得过来看看这个
Detectives, you need to see this.
我们在墙上发现了一处暗柜  看看吧
We found a false panel in the wall. Take a look.
绳索  强力胶带...
Rope, duct tape...
布  手套...
rags, gloves...
氯仿
chloroform.
看来某人是要策划一出绑架
Looks like somebody was planning an abduction.
他估计已经过了策划的阶段了
He might have went past the planning phase.
荧光棒使用之后
Glow sticks last, what,
能持续有24到48小时吧
24 to 48 hours once activated?
这些还在亮着
And they're still glowing.
说明他在过去的两天内
Which means he must have used this bag
用过这一袋子东西了
within the last two days.
是啊
Yeah.
不过做了什么呢
But for what?
刚从鉴证科过来
Well, I just got off with CSU.
这块布上面检测到了氯仿
That rag tested positive for chloroform.
说明他用这个迷晕过某个人
So he must have used it to knock someone out.
这可不太像律师的作风啊
Not very lawyerly of Mr. Pitbull.
钢丝钳  警报器原理图
So, wire cutters, alarm schematics,
夜视仪  还有荧光棒
night-vision goggles, and glow sticks.
他是想闯入某个地方  可是哪里呢
He's breaking in somewhere. But where?
好  我来查查记录
All right, I'll check the blotters,
看看过去两天里有没有什么入室盗窃
see if there were any B&Es in the past two days,
看看有没有和里奇的案子有关的
see if I can link any of them to Richie's cases.
好的  别忘了也查查失踪人口报告
Yeah, and look into missing-persons reports.
还不能排除是绑架的可能
We still can't rule out an abduction.
好的
Yeah.
看看这个
Check this out.
城市名和日期
Cities and dates.
"2009年1月3日  西雅图
"January 3, 2009, Seattle.
2011年3月18日  塔尔萨"
March 18, 2011, Tulsa."
六个都是在过去五年里
Six of them all within the last five years.
你觉得这些是什么意思
What do you think that means?
让托瑞在数据库里查查这些
Have Tory run this through the database,
看看能找到什么
see if she can find anything.
看看她能不能追查到里奇
And let's see if she can trace where Richie was
给他前妻打电话的时候在哪里
when he made that phone call to his ex.
你觉得这些和医院里的那个女孩有关联吗
You think any of this is connected to that girl at the hospital?
不  那就是起简单的交通事故...
No, that was a straight-up car accident --
和这些应该都没有关系
Nothing that speaks to any of this.
一定有人知道里奇究竟做了什么
But someone out there has to know what Richie was up to.
也许我们可以问问桑普森先生
Well, maybe we should ask Mr. Sampson.
桑普森先生是谁
Who's Mr. Sampson?
不知道  不过这是他的夜视镜
I don't know, but these are his night-vision goggles.
是的  是我的
Yeah. They're mine.
你怎么认识死者的  桑普森先生
How did you know the victim, Mr. Sampson?
我给里奇干过几次活
I did work for Richie here and there.
监视  搜集情报什么的
Surveillance, information gathering --
一般私家侦探干的那些事
The usual P.I. stuff.
他前几天来找我  借这些东西
He came to me a couple days ago, asking to borrow them.
他有没有说要用它们做什么
Did he say what he needed them for?
有时他会多给我一些钱
Sometimes he would slip me some extra cash
就是让我别多管闲事
not to ask questions.
你还帮过他什么别的事吗
Anything else you helped him with?
是的  他问了我一些警报电路图的事
Yeah -- he had some questions about alarm schematics.
就像
Like...
就像是这种的吗
like these?
是的
Yeah.
那氯仿呢  桑普森先生
What about chloroform, Mr. Sampson?
也是你给他的吗
Did you give him that, too?
不是  他有氯仿
No. He had chloroform?
是的  怎么了  怎么回事
Yeah. Why? What's wrong?
我给他夜视镜的时候
When I gave him the goggles,
问他还需不需要什么别的东西
I asked if there was anything else he needed.
他说了一些话
He said something.
我以为他是在开玩笑
I thought he was joking.
他说什么了
What did he say?
我问我
He asked me...
"处理尸体的最好办法是什么"
"What's the best way to get rid of a body?"
"处理尸体"
"Get rid of a body"?
我现在开始认为这位律师
I'm starting to think that our lawyer for the little guy
真的绑架了人
did abduct someone.
是的  而且还杀了人
Yeah, and apparently killed them.
或许这就是他所说的"结算债务"
Maybe that's what he meant by "Settling a debt."
可债务是指什么  他杀了谁
But what was the debt, whom did he kill,
还有他怎么会把命搭上
and how did it cost him his life?
我们得去问问莱恩和埃斯波
We need to check where Ryan and Espo are
那份失踪人员名单查得怎么样了
with that missing-persons list.
如果我们能找到里奇
If we can find a connection between Richie
和名单上人的关系
and one of the people on the list,
我们就能有答案了
that should give us some answers.
话说莱恩和埃斯波去哪了
Where are Ryan and Espo, anyway?
我好像看到他们去审讯室了
I think I saw them go into interrogation.
他们在审讯谁
Who are they interrogating?
有什么我们不知道的嫌犯吗
Hey, is there another suspect that we don't know about?
怎么回事
What's going on?
我不能说
I'm... not supposed to say.
我
I --
也不能让别人进去
Or let anyone in.
好吧
Okay.
他们在干什么
What are they doing?
没搞错吧
Are you seeing what I'm seeing?
狗屁扭伤了
"Sprained," my ass!
他的膝盖明明没事
His knee is fine.
蠢朋克的《真走运》
Daft Punk, "Get lucky."
我打赌他们肯定把歌词改成"你有罪"了
I bet they're changing the lyrics to "You're guilty."
太棒了
That's good!
卡塞尔  他骗我们是为了让你跟他打赌
Castle, he lied to us just so he could sucker you into a bet,
你上当了
which you fell for.
他会后悔的
He's gonna regret this.
我们必须要赢
Now we have to win.
靠什么  我们冲澡时的表演吗
With what -- our shower routine?
两位  有空吗
Hey, guys. Got a sec?
我好像查到些什么
I think I've got something.
我之前一直没能把那份名单
I haven't had any luck connecting that list
和你给我的日期以及城市联系起来
of dates and cities you gave me,
但是当我追踪里奇昨天跟他的前任通话时
But when I traced Richie's call to his ex yesterday,
我发现了点有意思的事
I did find something interesting.
电话是从哈德逊克罗顿附近的
Turns out it pinged off a cell tower
信号塔拨出的
near Croton-on-Hudson.
那里离城市北部有一个小时
That's an hour north of the city.
里奇去哪干什么
What was Richie doing up there?
不知道  但是通过利用附近信号塔
I don't know, but by triangulating the signal
进行三角定位
off of other nearby cell towers,
我找到了一个很精确的区域
I was able to dial in a more precise location.
蒙特罗斯国家森林
Montrose State Forest?
更准确地说  那通电话是从这个停车场打出的
To be exact, the call came from this parking lot,
就在通往一大片森林的小道起点
right at a trailhead into this large wooded area.
一片很偏僻  位于正北方的森林
An out-of-the-way forest well north of the city.
你是不是也觉得这是...
Now, is it just me, or does that sound like...
处理尸体的最佳地点
The perfect place to get rid of a body.
你知道这个希望不大  对吧
You know this is a long shot, right?
如果就像托瑞说的  里奇把车停在那
If Richie parked in the lot, like Tory said,
那他就会沿着路走到这
then he would have come down this trail right here.
考虑到拖着一具尸体走不远
And given how unwieldy it is to carry a dead body --
这是研究的结果  不是我的经验
that's research, not experience --
那他不会走太远就会将其埋掉
Well, then he wouldn't have gone very far before burying it,
所以我们只需要在这一大片区域内
which means we just have to look for freshly disturbed dirt
找最近被翻动过的泥土
in this, you know, general area...
比如  就是这里
Like, right here.
是的  我刚才说了  希望不大
Yeah. Like I said, long shot.
就像我们能赢的概率
Just like our chances at winning that competition.
别这么消极
Don't think like that. Come on.
我的搭档要有积极的态度
I need my partner to have a positive attitude.
是的  或许你应该在选搭档之前
Yeah, then maybe you should have checked with your partner
跟搭档商量一下
before signing her up for this.
有什么大不了  会很有趣的
What's the big deal? It'll be fun!
卡塞尔  你没见过那帮傻瓜吗
Castle, did you see those knuckleheads?
如果我有一天成为了
I mean, what if I want to be a captain one day
我们警区的警监
of my own precinct?
我希望他们能严肃对待我
I kind of need people to take me seriously.
是这样的  相信我
They do. Trust me.
而且我希望能一直这样下去
And I'd like to keep it that way,
如果我在整个警局的人面前像傻子一样表演
which won't be possible if I'm acting like an idiot
那是肯定不可能的
in front of the entire police force.
那这样行不行
Okay. How about this?
我们做一些简单  不失尊严又优雅的事
We do something simple, dignified, elegant.
比如...
Something like...
一片款冬花
A patch of tussilago.
-我没听说过  -不是  不是
- I don't know that one. - No, no.
记不记得蕾妮说里奇的裤子上
Remember Lanie said that there was yellow pollen
有一些款冬花的花粉
on Richie's pants from a tussilago flower?
看看这一片黄色的花
Check out this little yellow patch right here
大约到脚踝的高度
about ankle high.
在
Yeah.
里奇真的把人埋在这里
Richie did bury someone out here.
关于那件事
Look, about the routine...
我知道你在担心  不过
I know you're worried, but --
没事的  卡塞尔  我们做什么没关系
It's okay, Castle. It doesn't matter what we do.
就要这种精神
Hey, that's the spirit!
最后都会以悲剧收场
It's gonna be a disaster.
不要这种精神
That's not the spirit.
我可能会被绊倒  衣服可能会滑落
I'm probably gonna trip, my dress is gonna split,
视频会被疯传
video's gonna go viral.
你现在有点多虑了
Okay, now you're just sounding paranoid.
怎么会有这种想法
Where is this coming from?
我的意思是  卡塞尔  这都有可能发生
I'm just saying, Castle, it could happen.
盖茨警监不上台表演
I mean, there's a reason why Captain Gates
是有她的道理的
doesn't get up on the stage and have fun.
我一直都以为
I just always assumed
她是真的做不到
it was because she was genetically incapable of it.
你想让我取消吗
You want me to cancel?
不  不
No! No.
这样也会让我丢脸的
That would just make me lose face in another way.
我碰到了什么东西
I just hit something.
是尸体袋
That's a body bag.
把袋子放下  离尸体远一些
Put the bag down and step away from the body.
我想我们刚给自己挖好了坟墓
I think we may just have dug our own graves.
我什么都没听见
I don't hear anything.
我也是
Me neither.
他在干什么
What's he doing?
他走了
He's gone.
什么
What?
尸体也不见了  他把尸体偷走了
So's the body! He stole the body.
为什么会有人来偷尸体
Why would anyone steal a body?
他肯定跟这个案子有所关联
He must be connected to this somehow.
也许他跟里奇是一伙的
Maybe he and Richie are partners.
或许是他们一起杀那个人
Maybe they killed that person together.
之后会有时间来讨论这个的
Well, there'll be time for questions later.
现在我们得找个法子
Right now, we just have to find a way
在他回来前把束线带割断
to saw through these zip tie before he gets back.
他把我们的钥匙和手机拿走了  所以
Yes, well, he took our keys and our phones, so...
等等
Oh! Wait a minute.
作为私家侦探培训的一部分  我看了
As part of my P.I. training, I saw a video
怎么把束线手铐弄断的视频
on how to break these zip-tie cuffs.
你只需要拿它们
All you have to do is just hit them
用尽全力砸自己的屁股
as hard as you can against your ass!
视频上说可能需要多尝试几次
It said it might take a few tries.
-没有用  -不会的
- It's not working. - No.
但往好的方面想  我觉得
But on the bright side, I think
我们想到了几个新的舞蹈动作
we came up with a new move for our dance routine.
玩笑开得太早
Too soon?
好了
Yes! Oh!
太好了
Sweet.
他把尸体偷走了吗
He stole the body?
派一队人到那片林子去看有没有蛛丝马迹
Send a team up to those woods to comb for trace evidence
查一下这些束线带上的DNA
and check these zip ties for DNA.
你们看到了那个人吗
Did you get a look at this guy?
他戴了面具而且出现在我们后面
He was masked, came up behind us,
一直没有在我们面前露脸
kept us facing away from him the whole time.
从失踪人口上有查到什么吗
Anything from missing persons?
里奇的生活中有人失踪吗
Anyone in Richie's life that disappeared?
我们查了三州地区
Well, we've looked into every disappearance and break-in
所有的失踪和非法闯入的案件
in the tri-state area.
目前还没有发现他们和里奇间的关联
So far, no connection to any one of them and Richie.
我查了他已知的合伙人  客户
And I, uh, checked with known associates, clients,
还有他告过的人
people he was suing.
他们都没有失踪
They're all accounted for.
确实有人在运尸袋里  再深入调查一下
Yeah. Well, somebody was in that bag, so let's dig deeper.
你可以不用装瘸了
Oh. And, uh, you can lose the limp.
我们看到你们排练了
We saw you rehearsing.
再补充一点  不再是今生之罪了
If I might add, it's no "I've had the crime of my life."
那么
Well...
能赢你们俩还是挺好的
It's still good enough to take the both of you down.
算了吧  伙计们
Come on, guys.
比赛不是最重要的
This isn't really about the competition.
都是为了慈善  不是吗
It's about doing our best for a good cause, right?
一切都是为了比赛
It's about the competition.
真棒  太棒了
Well! Bravo! And brava!
太棒了  亲爱的太精彩了
Wonderful. Darlings, just wonderful.
谢谢
Thank you.
你之前还担心呢  看到了吧
And you were worried. See?
这既优雅又高贵
It's elegant, dignified,
最重要的是  这是要赢得奖杯的表演
and, above all, a trophy-winning performance.
我说的对吗  妈妈
Am I right, mother?
会是的  等我帮你们排练好
Well, it will be when I'm done with it.
我要稍稍调整一些细节
I'm gonna just need to tweak a few little things.
我真的很希望你们能做那个劈叉
And I do wish you would go for that split.
-可我  -我要留你来说服她
- Well, I -- - Okay. Well, I will leave you to convince Ginger.
我很快就回来
I will be right back.
等等  你要去哪里
Wait. Where -- w-where are you going?
我要给埃斯波西托打电话
I'm gonna call Esposito.
我觉得是时候增加赌注了
I think it's time we raise the stakes on that bet.
什么  卡塞尔
What? Castle...
亲爱的  别担心他了
Oh, darling, don't you worry about him.
不要担心奖杯
Do not worry about that trophy,
因为在最后的表演中
because the only thing that anybody
大家唯一会记住的
is going to remember from the final performance
就是你像天使一样歌唱
is that you sound like an angel.
玛莎  我做不到
Except, Martha, I won't.
你当然可以  你刚刚就做到了
Well, of course you will. You just did.
不  玛莎  那是因为只有你和理查德
No, Martha. That's because it was just you and Rick.
我们没有公开地在陌生人面前
We weren't in public in front of strangers.
不会吧  舞台恐惧
Oh, no. Stage fright.
更像是唱歌恐惧
Well, it's -- it's -- it's more like song fright.
我是说  我的心会跳得很快
I mean, my heart just starts palpitating
并且冒汗  我的喉咙就像堵住了一样
and I start sweating and my throat just chokes up.
我懂  我明白
I know. I know. I know.
这很正常  确实很糟糕
It's classic, and it's awful.
那为什么
And why in the world
理查德会让你参加呢
would Richard sign you up for this?
他不知道
He doesn't know.
宝贝  你得告诉他
Oh, honey. You have to tell him.
我不想让他失望
Oh, I-I don't want to let him down.
他太想参加了
He wants this so badly.
我想帮他
I want to give it to him.
但我只是  我不知道我能不能
But I just -- I don't know that I can.
我已经等不及看他们脸上的表情
I cannot wait to see the looks on their faces
当他们看了我们的表演之后
when they get a load of our routine.
我可以很清楚地想象到
Yeah, I can imagine it v-vividly.
相信我  肯定很棒
Oh, trust me -- it'll be great.
如果真的会很棒的话
If it's gonna be so great,
为什么我们不把赌注再加大一点
then why don't we up the bet again?
埃斯波西托  你有什么想法
Well, Esposito, what did you have in mind?
抱歉各位  什么打赌都没了
Sorry, fellas. All bets are off.
刚得到总局的消息
I just heard from 1pp.
坎莫尔重新安排了他的日程  他回来了
Kimmel rearranged his schedule, and he's back in.
所以  不幸的是
Oh -- so, unfortunately,
卡塞尔先生  我们不需要麻烦你了
we will not be needing your services, Mr. Castle.
真的吗
Really?
可我们都排练好了
But we rehearsed and everything.
这我可管不了
Out of my hands.
这没完
This isn't over.
-伙计们  我们找到他了  -谁
- Hey, guys. We got him. - Who?
那个在树林里从你们手上抢走尸体的人
That guy who jacked you for that body in the woods.
当鉴证组赶到那时
When CSU went up there,
他们在树上发现了些东西
they noticed something in the trees --
由运用传感器触发的摄像头
Cameras triggered by motion sensors
来统计野生生物的数量
to carry out wildlife census.
猜我们找到了什么野生生物
Guess what kind of wildlife we found.
麦克·桑普森
Mike Sampson.
里奇的私家侦探
Richie's P.I.
纽约警局
NYPD!
让我看到你的双手  现在
Let me see your hands -- now!
麦克  尸体在哪
Where is it, Mike? Where's the body?
怎么了  你们在说什么
What's going on? What are you talking about?
搜查他的住处
Search his place.
埃斯波  打开后备箱
Espo, pop the trunk.
把手放在车上
Hands on the car.
好吧
All right.
在这
It's here.
麦克  运尸袋里的是谁
Who's in the bag, Mike?
什么啊这是
What the...
关于里奇和假人  桑普森都不愿意谈
Sampson's not talking -- about Richie or the dummy.
我不明白
I don't get it.
为什么里奇把做撞击试验的假人
Why would Richie bury a crash-test dummy
埋在偏僻的地方  为什么桑普森要偷走它
in the middle of nowhere, and why would Sampson steal it?
我不知道  但他有可能故意
I don't know, but he probably told us that story
告诉我们里奇抛尸的故事
about Richie dumping a body
这样我们就能带他找到它
so that we could lead him straight to it.
事实证明假人并不是
Well, it turns out that dummy's not the only thing
桑普森偷走的唯一东西
that Sampson stole.
警员在他的公寓发现了里奇丢失的客户资料
UNIs found Richies's missing client files
并且都被撕毁了
in his apartment, shredded.
这肯定和里奇的某个案子有关
This must have something to do with one of Richie's cases.
但是哪一个呢
Yeah, but which one?
你知道吗  如果桑普森不愿说
You know, if Sampson won't talk,
也许那个假人会告诉我们
then maybe the dummy will.
你知道我是医生  不是傀儡师对吧
You do know I'm a doctor, not a puppeteer?
对呀  因为你是医生  我才希望你能
Yes. And as a doctor, I was hoping that you could tell us
告诉我们这假人有什么特别之处
what's so special about this dummy.
我可以告诉你们它的特别之处
I'll tell you what's special about it.
这假人被谋杀了
This dummy has been murdered.
谋杀
Murdered?
看到它胸口的小孔了吗
See the holes in his chest?
看起来像很小的弹孔
They look like little bullet holes.
也可以算是了
That's basically what they are.
就我所见  成因是有巨大外力推动的
As far as I can tell, they were made by small metal pieces
小型金属片
projected with significant force.
什么能导致这样的情况
What would explain that?
很难说
It's hard to say.
这种假人用处广泛
Lots of people use these dummies --
汽车公司  航空公司
Car companies, the airline industry,
还有军队
the military.
可能是某人用来检测爆炸物或者
So someone could have been testing the effects
新型枪械的效果的
of an I.E.D. or a new firearm.
我觉得不是枪械
I don't think it's a firearm.
三个孔
Three holes...
心脏周围有三片游离金属
Three bits of flying metal around the heart.
这话在哪里听过
Where have we heard that before?
巨锤的客户  斗牛犬想撬走的那位
Hammer's client -- the one Pitbull tried to poach.
我记得的最后一件事就是收旧货的卡车
Last thing I remember was that salvage truck
冲进了我面前的绿化带
hitting the median before me.
那是金属碎片就一通乱飞
That's when the metal started to fly.
救护人员说我很幸运  差点就没命了
The paramedic said I was lucky, that I almost died.
朱迪  你还记得这个人吗
Um, Jody, do you remember this guy?
记得  斗牛犬
Yeah -- The Pitbull.
他想为我代理  但我已经有律师了
He wanted to represent me, but I already had a lawyer.
然后他问了很多关于车祸的细节
But then he wouldn't stop asking about the accident,
一副不相信的样子
like he didn't believe what happened.
朱迪  你当时开的是什么车
Jody, what kind of car were you driving?
我不确定  车是租来的
I'm not sure. It was a rental.
怎么每个人都这么问我
Why does everyone keep asking that?
还有谁问了
Who's been asking?
斗牛犬  还有昨天那位女士
The Pitbull and the lady who was here yesterday.
哪位女士
What lady?
她说她是我保险公司的业务员
She said she was from my insurance company.
我醒的时候  她正在看我的病情表
When I woke up, she was looking at my chart.
她问了我的伤情
She asked me about my injuries
还问了很多车的事
and wanted to know all about the car.
讲不通
That doesn't make any sense.
这些信息保险公司都能从
The insurance company would have that information
车祸报告中找到
from the accident report.
你可以向画像师描述一下她的长相吗
Do you think you could describe her to a sketch artist?
可以
Yeah.
好的  还有件事
Okay. And, um, one more thing.
你租车的公司叫什么名字
What was the name of the car-rental company?
根据租车公司的信息
According to the rental firm,
朱迪开的是辆莫德斯托轿车
Jody was driving a Modesto Sedan.
我没有找到能解释她伤情的安全召回事件
Now, I couldn't find any safety recalls to explain her injuries,
凭直觉  我又查了找到的那张纸上
but on a hunch, I checked the cities and dates
列出的城市和时间
on that slip of paper that we found.
我发现每起
Turns out that each one
涉及莫德斯托的车祸
corresponded to a Modesto car accident
均出现了司机胸口受到刺伤的情况
where the driver suffered puncture wounds to the chest.
就像朱迪·埃文斯和撞击试验假人
Just like Jody Evans and that crash-test dummy.
但所有案子里  这伤口
Yeah, but in each case, the wounds
都被归为了外来因素
were attributed to something outside the vehicle --
马路上来的碎片  甚至还有枪伤的说法
Road debris, even gunshots.
根据碎片速度
Given the velocity of the shrapnel,
可以肯定这是气囊的缺陷导致的
this must be related to a defect in the airbags.
根据假人上的伤口
And judging by the holes in that dummy,
莫德斯托是知道此缺陷存在的
Modesto was aware of that defect
却选择了闭口不提
and chose to sweep it under the rug.
里奇发现了一个被掩盖的真相
Richie was onto a cover-up.
是啊  而且他很可能本来就知情
Yeah, one that he might have been a part of.
我查了里奇五年前就职的
I looked into that big-time law firm
那家有名的律师事务所
where Richie used to work five years ago
那是他还不是斗牛犬
before he became the Pitbull.
猜猜他们最大的客户是谁
Guess who their biggest client was.
莫德斯托汽车
Modesto Motors.
而且他们的案子都是里奇处理的
Yeah. And Richie handled their account.
大概五年前  莫德斯托差点破产了
You know, about five years, Modesto was nearly bankrupt.
所以它们没有选择花几百万来修复隐患
So rather than spend millions of dollars to fix the problem,
而是在召回的成本
they decided that the cost of recall
和人身安全之间  选择了前者
outweighed the potential cost to human life.
看来里奇良心上很过不去
Looks like Richie's conscience couldn't take it.
他染上酗酒和吸毒
That problem he had with drinking and drugs
都是第一起事件后几个月开始的
started just a few months after that first accident.
里奇跟里克说要还的债
That debt Richie told Derek he was settling --
指的是因果报应
it was a karmic one.
他想弥补这件事  揭露真相
He wanted to make it right, expose the cover-up.
他必须证明莫德斯托在有人因此丧命前
He needed to prove that Modesto knew about the defect
就知道缺陷的事
even before people started dying.
那个撞击试验假人  就是他的铁证
That crash-test dummy -- that was his smoking gun.
这也解释了撬门工具
Which explains the break-in equipment.
他需要从莫德斯托那把假人偷出来
He needed it to steal the dummy from Modesto.
怪不得里奇疑神疑鬼
No wonder Richie was paranoid
要把假人埋在森林
and buried that dummy in the woods.
如果缺陷的真相被揭穿
Guys, if the truth about the defect came out,
莫德斯托可能会
then Modesto would be liable
面临上亿的损失
for hundreds of millions of dollars in damages.
他知道他们会不顾一切的抢回假人
He knew they'd stop at nothing to get it back.
这理论很棒
Okay, this is a hell of a theory,
但现在里奇死了  文件也销毁了
but with Richie dead, the files all destroyed,
如果无法证明莫德斯托
and with absolutely no connection
和假人的联系
between the dummy and modesto,
那这些也就只是理论而已
It's just that -- it's a theory.
可不只是个理论
Oh, it's more than a theory.
我们刚拿到根据朱迪的描述
We just got that sketch back from Jody
那位去看望她  自称是
of the woman who visited her
保险公司业务员的女人的素描图
claiming to be from an insurance company.
眼熟吗
Look familiar?
里奇的前妻
Richie's ex.
她和这些事有什么关系啊
What the hell does she have to do with any of this?
她刚刚被撬走  离开了和里奇曾一起工作的
She was recently poached from the law firm
那个律师事务所
that she and Richie worked at.
现在她是莫德斯托首席律师
She's now lead counsel for Modesto.
里奇就成了威胁
Richie was a threat.
他知道那些人因何丧命
He knew where the bodies were buried.
所以她前妻决定把他也干掉
So his ex-wife decided to add him to the pile.
为什么又找我来  知道的我都说了
I'm not sure why I'm here. I've told you everything I know.
不  你没有全说
No. Not everything.
你没告诉我们你现在是莫德斯托汽车的
You didn't tell us that you were lead counsel
首席律师
for modesto motors,
你也没告诉我们气囊有缺陷的事
and you didn't tell us about the airbags.
就是那些弹出时能在人体上
You know, those airbags with the habit
打穿小洞的气囊  像朱迪·埃文斯那样
of putting holes in people, like Jody Evans.
你说什么啊
Excuse me?
莱斯纳女士  里奇那天为什么给你打电话
Ms. Resner, why did Richie really call you the other day?
是想先提醒你一下吧
Was it to give you a little heads-up?
看在过去交情的份上
You know -- for old times' sake?
因为过去他帮助掩盖缺陷时
Because that defect he helped cover up back then,
你也参与了
you were in on that, too.
他想公开此事
He was going public with it,
不希望你到时候一无所知
and he didn't want you to be blindsided.
但你不能允许他这么做
But you couldn't let that happen --
对莫德斯托不利对你更不利
not to Modesto and certainly not to you.
所以你灭了他的口
So you had him silenced.
你认为是我杀了我前夫
You think I killed my ex-husband?
探长  里奇的死和我毫无关系
Detective, I had nothing to do with Richie's death.
还有  也不存在什么缺陷或者隐瞒真相
And, by the way, there is no defect or cover-up.
里奇可不这么认为
Richie knew otherwise.
事实上  为了证明此事他还干过非法闯入
In fact, he committed a break-in just to prove it.
我们发现三天前莫德斯托汽车的
We found that a silent alarm was tripped
仓库有一个无声警铃被触发过
at a Modesto Motors storage facility three nights ago.
但警方赶到时
But when police responded,
负责人却声称是意外触发的
they were told it was set off by mistake.
然而那晚救护车被叫来
Yet an ambulance was called there that night
治疗一位吸入氯仿的警卫
to treat a guard for chloroform inhalation.
我不知道那件事
I'm not familiar with that incident.
那你知道这个吗
Well, are you familiar with this?
这是你掩盖真相的证据
It's evidence of your cover-up.
如果这假人是通过非法手段
If this dummy was illegally obtained
从莫德斯托仓库盗取
from a Modesto storage facility,
那它依旧是莫德斯托的财产
then it is the property of ,
我们想要取回
and we'd like it back.
那当然
I'm sure you would,
尤其是考虑到这个假人会导致你的公司
especially considering it could cost your company
数百万美元的损失
hundreds of millions of dollars.
所以你才会雇这个人取回假人
Which is why you hired this man to retrieve it.
我们正在核查他的财务记录
We're looking into his financial records right now.
早晚会将他和莫德斯托联系起来
It's only a matter of time before we connect him to Modesto.
你完全搞错了  探长
You're barking up the wrong tree, detective.
莫德斯托有内部调查员
Modesto has its own in-house investigators.
如果我们想取回假人  如你所说
If we wanted to recover this dummy, as you claim,
我们为什么要把如此敏感之事交给外人
why would we entrust such a sensitive task to an outsider?
但我见过这个人
But I have seen this man before.
在哪
Where?
圣西蒙医院门口
In front of St. Simon's hospital.
他坐在车里  跟某人谈话
He was sitting in a car, conferring with someone else.
跟谁谈话
Conferring with whom?
欠你一次现金和解
Owed a cash settlement?
巨锤出场
It's hammer time.
我会大锤特锤
I'll pound and pound away
直到拿到你应得的现金
till I've nailed down the cash you've got coming.
任何阻挡你的人
Anyone gets in your way,
都得先过我这关  草原巨锤
they'll have to deal with me -- the Savannah Hammer.
里奇·法科就是落得这下场吗
Is that what happened to Richie Falco?
他阻碍了你  就被你锤死了
He got in your way, so you pounded him till he was dead?
不好意思  我们正在拍...
Excuse me! We're filming h--
卡塞尔先生  希望你
Mr. Castle, I will thank you
带着你那空口无凭的指控到外面去等着
and your ridiculous allegations to wait outside.
不再是空口无凭了
They're not just allegations -- not anymore.
麦克·桑普森供出了你
Mike Sampson gave you up.
一名目击证人看到你俩在一起
A witness placed the two of you together,
桑普森不希望跟
and Sampson was more than eager
谋杀沾上关系
to distance himself from the murder.
但他供认闯入里奇的办公室
But he did admit to breaking into Richie's office
并从我们手中劫走碰撞试验假人
and hijacking the crash-test dummy from us
都是因为你雇了他
because you paid him to.
我不知道你们在说什么
I really don't know what you're talking about.
你知道
Oh, I think you do.
你知道莫德斯托会支付数百万美元
You knew Modesto would pay millions
赎回那假人
to get that dummy back.
你如此确定  甚至承诺给麦克分成
Matter of fact, you were so sure, you promised Mike a cut.
太疯狂了
This is crazy.
我从没雇人偷东西
I never paid anyone to steal anything.
我也没杀斗牛犬  我有不在场证明
And I didn't kill the Pitbull. I have an alibi.
你没有了
No. Not anymore.
为你提供不在场证明的人
Once your alibi found out
得知她面临谋杀从犯的指控
she was facing accessory-to-murder charges,
她撤回了作证  承认你雇了她
she recanted and admitted that you paid her.
我们找到了电击枪  巨锤
We found the taser, Hammer --
在你车后箱  就在撬胎棒旁边
In the back of your car, right next to that tire iron.
你虽然将其清洗过  但你忘了车毯上
Which you bleached, but you forgot about the droplets
的血液残留
of blood residue on the carpet.
你认为当我们发现那与
What do you think is gonna happen
里奇的血样匹配会发生什么
when we test it against Richie's dna?
都结束了
It's over.
我想不通为什么
You know, what I can't figure out is why.
为什么
Why?
因为他看不出那假人是个金矿
Because he couldn't see that that dummy was a gold mine.
他只想追求正义
And all he wanted was justice?
你跟他一样天真
You're as naive as he was.
走吧  巨锤
Let's go, Hammer.
是啊
Yeah.
巨锤出场
It's slammer time.
看看是谁出现了
Look who decided to show up.
你们去哪了  你们错过了比赛
Where were you guys? You missed the competition.
抱歉  伙计们
Yeah. Sorry, you guys.
我们在国家运输安全委员会录口供耽搁了
We got held up giving a statement at NTSB.
但欣慰的是  他们将对
But you'll be happy to know they're launching
莫德斯托汽车展开全面调查
a full investigation of Modesto Motors.
看来斗牛犬最终得到了想要的
Well, looks like Pitbull's gonna get what he wanted --
为所有缺陷受害者讨回公道
Justice for all the victims of that defect.
你们表现如何
Yeah. What about you gentlemen?
你们如愿以偿了吗
Did you get what you wanted at the show?
这么说吧
Well, um, let's put it this way --
我们不再是两届冠军了
We are no longer two-time champs.
三连冠  宝贝
Three years in a row, baby!
真厉害
That's awesome!
真为你们感到高兴
Oh, I'm so happy for you guys.
非常棒
Yes. Very nice, very nice.
恭喜  尽管今年的比赛
Congratulations, even though the, uh, field of competition
对手实力较弱
was a little light this year.
说到这个  不是有个赌注
Speaking of which, isn't there a certain bet
该算一算了吗
that needs settling?
对  公开声明
Oh, right -- the dedication.
就看字体弄多大了
I guess it's just a matter of how big to make that font size.
不是吧
Seriously? Come on.
我们都没有机会正面交锋
Guys, we didn't even get a chance to square off.
所以我们不跟你们计较
Which is why we're not gonna hold you to it.
不跟你算账了  卡塞尔
You're off the hook, Castle.
谢谢  你们真大度
Thank you. Thank you. That's very big of you.
尤其考虑到我们本可以击溃你们的
Especially considering we would have kicked your asses.
说大话
Uh... now, you gonna talk smack?
那咱们
Well, then we are gonna settle this...
现在在这里对决
right here, right now.
咱把桌子都移开
Why don't we just clear all these desks,
硬碰硬  让分局的人决定胜负
go head-to-head, let the precinct decide!
不  你们想显摆显摆  让给你们
No. You want bragging rights? They're yours.
我们的舞步对你们来说  太牛掰
Our routine's too good for you, anyway.
就知道他怂了
That's what I thought.
可不是
Yeah.
你什么时候会拒绝挑战
Since when do you turn down a challenge?
他们知道我们更厉害  没必要让他们出糗
Oh, they know we're better. No sense in embarrassing them.
你知道了  是吧
You know, don't you?
知道什么
Know what?
所以我们才会退赛
That's why we got pulled from the lineup.
坎莫尔是你好友
Kimmel's your bud.
肯定是你打电话给他  让他表演
You must have called him and told him to perform
我们就不用出场了
so we wouldn't have to.
我就不用出场了
Or...so that I wouldn't have to.
我可能偷听到了你和我母亲的谈话
I...may have overheard you talking to my mother.
你这么做是为了我
You did that for me?
你为我会做出同样的牺牲
No more of a sacrifice than what you were gonna do for me.
凯特  你为什么不直说
Kate, why wouldn't you just say something?
我不想让你看低我
I didn't want you to think less of me.
我不想让其他人知道
And I really didn't want anyone else to know, so...
蠢死了
Stupid.
不蠢  人之常情
No. Not stupid. Just human.
不能为观众表演
Aren't you disappointed
你一点都不失望吗
you're not gonna be able to perform for an audience?
我在乎的观众只有你
The only audience I care about is you.
*你不知道吗  小笨蛋*
*Don't you know, little fool*
*你永远赢不了*
*You never can win*
*用用你的心智*
*Use your mentality*
*在现实中醒过来吧*
*Wake up to reality*
*每当我如此  只会想到你*
*But each time I do, just the thought of you?*
*令我在开始之前  立刻停止*
*Makes me stop before I begin*
*因为我把你*
*'cause I've got you*
*深深地迷住了*
*Under my skin*